<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>htb on hackerwasii</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://hackerwasii.com/tags/htb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in htb on hackerwasii</description>
    <generator>hackerwasii.com</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hackerwasii.com/tags/htb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Boom Bashed 🧨💥</title>
      <link>https://hackerwasii.com/posts/boom-bashed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackerwasii.com/posts/boom-bashed/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Bashed is a retired HackTheBox machine, rated easy and rightfully. We&amp;rsquo;ll start by finding a hidden web shell to quickly gaining root level access due to misconfigured permissions to users.
Reconnaissance nmap scan Starting the reconnaissance with an initial Nmap scan.
nmap -sC -sV -oA nmap/bashed 10.129.183.146 -sC: run default nmap scripts
-sV: detect service version
-oA: output all formats and store in file nmap/bashed
Nmap scan report for 10.129.183.146 Host is up (0.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash and the Shellshock ⚡️</title>
      <link>https://hackerwasii.com/posts/shellshock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackerwasii.com/posts/shellshock/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Introduction to ShellShock ShellShock Vulnerability [CVE-2014-6271], also known as Bashdoor, is a family of security bugs in the Unix Bash shell, the first of which was disclosed on 24 September 2014. Shellshock could enable an attacker to cause Bash to execute arbitrary commands and gain unauthorized access to many Internet-facing services, such as web servers, that use Bash to process requests.
Shellshock is a privilege escalation vulnerability that offers a way for users of a system to execute commands that should be unavailable to them.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting PHP deserialization 🔐</title>
      <link>https://hackerwasii.com/posts/php-deserialization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackerwasii.com/posts/php-deserialization/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Intro to Insecure deserialization Serialization is when an object in a programming language (say, a Java or PHP object) is converted into a format that can be stored or transferred. Whereas deserialization refers to the opposite: it’s when the serialized object is read from a file or the network and converted back into an object.
Insecure deserialization vulnerabilities happen when applications deserialize objects without proper sanitization. An attacker can then manipulate serialized objects to change the program’s flow.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From MSSQL to RCE 🚀</title>
      <link>https://hackerwasii.com/posts/mssql-rce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackerwasii.com/posts/mssql-rce/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Microsoft SQL Server is a relational database management system developed by Microsoft. As a database server, it is a software product with the primary function of storing and retrieving data as requested by other software applications—which may run either on the same computer or on another computer across a network (including the Internet). In this blog we&amp;rsquo;ll try to get remote code execution by exploiting MSSQL.
Enumeration Nmap Scan nmap -sC -sV -oA nmap/archetype 10.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>